The paper titled, The Formation Process of Winners and Losers in Momentum Investing,
论文《The Formation Process of Winners and Losers in Momentum Investing》
discusses how the trajectory of a stock is
讨论了股票的轨迹
an indicator for whether its momentum is accelerated or decelerated.
可以表示动量是加速还是减速动量
When a stock is recently showing higher returns,
当股票最近收益更高时
this paper refers to these as accelerated gains.
论文将其称为加速利得
When a stock is recently showing minimal positive returns,
当股票最近出现最低的正收益率时
the paper refers to these as decelerated gains.
论文将其称为减速利得
If you look at a stock price trajectory of an accelerated gain,
观察加速利得的股价轨迹
the shape will be convex.
会发现形状是凸曲线
In case you can't remember what a convex curve looks like,
y = x^2 图形就是一种
the plot of y equals x squared is an example of a convex function.
凸曲线函数
Essentially, the trajectory is showing an accelerated increase.
它的轨迹是加速增长的
On the other hand,
另一方面
a stock price trajectory of a decelerated gain will have a concave shape.
减速利得的股价轨迹形状为凹曲线
As a reminder of what concave means,
y = √x￣ 图形
a plot of y equals the square root of x is an example of a concave function.
就属于凹曲线函数
The trajectory is showing a decelerated increase.
它的轨迹是减速增长的
We can also describe accelerated losses and decelerated losses as concave or convex.
我们还可以将加速损失和减速利得看做凹曲线或凸曲线
An accelerated loss has a concave shape.
加速损失具有凹形形状
You can imagine the plot of y equals negative x squared as a concave function.
可以将 y=-x^2 看做凹函数
A decelerated loss has a convex shape.
减速损失具有凸形形状
You can imagine the plot of y equals negative square root of x as a convex shape.
可以将 y=-√x￣ 看做凸函数
So far, we've described four general shapes.
到目前为止 我们描述了四种一般形状
What we want to point out is which type of
我们想要判断
trajectory may be preferred for going long or going short.
哪种轨迹更适合做多或做空
We'd say that an accelerated gain may have
我们认为加速利得
higher future returns compared to a decelerated gain,
比减速利得具有更高的未来收益率
if the starting and end points are the same.
如果起始和结束点一样的话
So, we would prefer to go long the accelerated gain,
所以我们做多加速利得股票
a bit more than the decelerated gain.
比减速利得股票多一点
We would also say that an accelerated loss is
并且我们认为加速损失
predictive of more negative returns compared to a decelerated loss.
比减速损失更能预测负收益率
So, all else being equal,
所以其他都相同的话
we would prefer to short the accelerated loss more than the decelerated loss.
我们愿意做空加速损失股票 而不是减速损失股票
An important point that might not be obvious to see in the paper is that we can
论文中没有明确指出的重要一点是
view the convexity or concavity of a curve in a relative terms.
我们可以相对地看待凸性或凹性
In other words, compared to a convex curve,
也就是说 与凸曲线相比
a straight line is relatively more concave.
直线相对更凹
Likewise, compared to a concave curve,
同理 与凹曲线相比
a straight line is relatively more convex.
直线相对更凸
You may recall with the example of the tortoise stock and the rabbit stock.
在乌龟和兔子的示例中
The tortoise stock trajectory look like a straight line,
乌龟股票的轨迹看起来像直线
whereas the rabbits stock was concave.
而兔子股票的轨迹看起来像凹线
So, relative to the rabbit stocks trajectory,
所以相对于兔子股票的轨迹来说
the tortoise stocks trajectory was more convex and
乌龟股票的轨迹更凸 根据刚刚的假说
also more predictive of higher future returns under this hypothesis.
乌龟股票的轨迹更能预测更高的未来收益率